Afonso Almendra Praça de Carvalho

Brazilian, 31 years, married [April 2017]

Rua Maria Eugênia 55, 202 - Humaitá - Rio de Janeiro - RJ - CEP: 22261-080 +55 21 3593.4758 // +55 21 97915.1515

afonsoinfo@gmail.com http://afonsopraca.com.br/ http://www.linkedin.com/in/afonsopraca https://github.com/afonso-praca

Summary

A brazilian software developer based in Rio de Janeiro, currently working for VTEX - E-commerce Cloud Application, a plataform that sells software as a service (SaaS). Mainly focused on front-end development, strongly skilled in JavaScript, and now working and searching mostly with AngularJS, Node.js and Go. Knows the e-commerce businnes.

Afonso started working as developer around 2005, as a freelancer developer. In 2009 he began working as lead developer at Caos! Design, where he solidified his knowledge of ActionScript and JavaScript, becoming, later, a partner of the business. Since 2012 works as a web developer of VTEX, working mostly in front end of the administration area of the e-commerce apps.

Nowadays he is the lead developer and product owner of the VTEX Pricing, the module responsible for the prices of all VTEX clients.

Experience

• Senior Software Developer [Team Lead] at VTEX

July 2012 - Present

Designs and develops Apps for E-commerce Suite. Participated in the development of various applications of e-commerce platform, developing mainly the front end of the administration area of the apps. With a Strongly customer centric approach.

• Business Partner and Lead Developer at Caos! vídeo & design

June 2009 - June 2012

Led the development of several websites. With attention to detail and commitment to quality.

• System Administrador at Ceperj - RJ

May 2008 - May 2009 Network and System Administrator

Languages

- English (Professional working proficiency)
- Spanish (Professional working proficiency)
- Portuguese (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

Afonso currenctly leads the VTEX Pricing Team. Working both in the back and front end of the system, he also works closely with some of VTEX clientss to get insights and to define the product roadmap very client centred.

Some of his skills are: Web Development, JavaScript, AngularJS, Git, HTTP, User Experience, Node.js, Express JS, Go

Education

- Universidade Federal do Estado do Rio de Janeiro

 Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Information Systems, 2008 2014
- SENAI-RJ
 Technology Course, Hardware and Computer Networks, 2005 2006
- Colégio Resende Anglo High School, 2002 - 2004

Some Interests

E-commerce, JavaScript, AngularJS, Software Architecture, SOA, REST APIs, Front-end Development, Project Management, Product Development.